<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

 <title>Tyler Tringas</title>
 <link href="http://www.tylertringas.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
 <link href="http://www.tylertringas.com/"/>
 <updated>2014-05-22T14:15:22+08:00</updated>
 <id>http://www.tylertringas.com</id>
 <author>
   <name>Tyler Tringas</name>
   <email></email>
 </author>

 
 <entry>
   <title>Shopify Workflow With Github</title>
   <link href="http://www.tylertringas.com/shopify-github-workflow"/>
   <updated>2014-05-19T00:00:00+08:00</updated>
   <id>http://www.tylertringas.com/shopify-workflow-with-github</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Recently had to write up my Shopify development workflow. I&amp;#39;m using Github and Shopify Theme Gem and it seems to work pretty well. Love to hear any feedback of course.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Pull latest code base from github&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Create a new development branch with the pattern [version]-[name]. As best as possible use &lt;a href=&quot;http://semver.org/&quot;&gt;semantic versioning&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot; data-lang=&quot;text&quot;&gt;git checkout -b 3.2.0-new-feature
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Head to the Shopify Admin &amp;gt; Themes. Duplicate a theme. If you created your branch from the master branch, then duplicate the live theme, if your development branch works of an existing unpublished development theme, then duplicate that theme.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Rename the duplicated theme the same as your branch name (i.e. 3.2.0-new-feature)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Install the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Shopify/shopify_theme&quot;&gt;Shopify Theme Gem&lt;/a&gt; and follow the installation process. Example:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot; data-lang=&quot;text&quot;&gt;gem install shopify_theme
theme configure [api_key] [password] [shop_url]
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note: this only needs to be done once&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Once this is installed, head the config.yml file in your development branch. You need to change the theme&lt;em&gt;id to your new development theme&amp;#39;s ID. Get the ID from the URL in the theme editor. Set theme&lt;/em&gt;id to this new ID and commit changes.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Now you can use the Shopify Theme Gem&amp;#39;s functions to sync your local version of the theme with the unpublished development theme you created (from the duplicate). Open console, cd to the directory and type:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot; data-lang=&quot;text&quot;&gt;theme watch
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The gem will now watch for saved files and automatically sync those files with your Shopify account. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Note: I recommend doing a test like adding a comment to confirm you are syncing changes with the development theme and NOT the live published theme.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;To see the effects of your changes just go to the theme manager and Preview the theme in the browser.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;When you&amp;#39;re finished either push a new branch to Github, or merge your changes into master and publish your development theme. The master branch should always match the published theme and development branches should always have an unpublished theme with the same name.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Meaningful Work For Digital Nomads</title>
   <link href="http://www.tylertringas.com/meaningful-work-digital-nomads"/>
   <updated>2014-05-14T00:00:00+08:00</updated>
   <id>http://www.tylertringas.com/meaningful-work-for-digital-nomads</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;m digital nomad-ing again. Put all my stuff in storage. Moved out of my Brooklyn apartment. Threw the macbook in the backpack and hit the road. A month in Thailand, much of it in Tonsai working on my rock climbing. Then a month in Bali, getting in to yoga for real for the first time. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;m definitely working fewer hours on this schedule but I am spending a lot of time working on Storemapper and freelance web development. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A friend sent me a link to this post: &lt;a href=&quot;http://milkthepigeon.com/2014/03/24/happiest-at-work/&quot;&gt;Why Being a Digital Nomad Sucks (And Why You Should Avoid It).&lt;/a&gt; It&amp;#39;s a pretty short post but the author&amp;#39;s point is that they were a digital nomad, traveled a lot, but the reality is, &amp;quot;people are often happier working, but only when we’re working on things that matter.&amp;quot; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I agree with this completely. There are only so many beaches and temples, museums, churches and breweries you can see traveling before you start itching to getting back to doing something that matters. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;m still not tired of drinking fresh coconuts though. Not sure if I ever will be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I agree with the central point of the post, that finding meaningful work is probably the path to happiness. But the rest of the post is complete BS. The title of the post doesn&amp;#39;t say &amp;quot;do meaningful work&amp;quot; it says &amp;quot;don&amp;#39;t be a digital nomad.&amp;quot; The implication here is that the two are mutually exclusive. Here&amp;#39;s where the post gets stupid&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I always seemed to meet two kinds of people though:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I would meet the typical 9-5 folks who were on vacation and wished they could have my life (it really wasn’t that great, they often just wanted to travel more).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And then I would meet people who told reality to piss off, and just did the stereotypical “rasta living on the beach and smoking weed” type lifestyle. Aka people that never really wanted to work a real job.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In other words, it was VERY polarized.
Working a typical life + vacation.
Versus:
Totally shunning the traditional life path, not getting married, not getting a real job, just focusing on life enjoyment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And it got me thinking…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If I had to polarize myself and pick just one of these, which one would I be happier doing?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Would I be happier with either of them?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sure, if you &lt;strong&gt;had&lt;/strong&gt; to choose one very few people would decide that an entire lifetime of listless wandering is not for them. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;But this is a false choice.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You don&amp;#39;t have to choose one. It&amp;#39;s not either or. This is not a &lt;em&gt;cake and eat it too&lt;/em&gt; situation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;One obvious option is that you can alternate between the two.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rolf Potts, author of &lt;a href=&quot;http://amzn.to/1sMmsKk&quot;&gt;Vagabonding&lt;/a&gt;, advocates for this style of alternating between work and long term traveling. So many of us are afraid to this because of the perceived risk to their careers. How will I explain that gap in my resume, they ask, assuming that rewarding careers are built with in a series of delicately daisy-chained promotions and advancements. Career loyalty is declining, creativity and versatility. I would hire someone with a great story over someone who has &amp;quot;put in the time&amp;quot; any day and I think the firms worth working for are increasingly on my side. Take a sabbatical, travel, learn a new skill and in the process show your old boss and company that they are not everything in your life. If you want your old job back I bet you&amp;#39;ll get it with a raise, but more likely you&amp;#39;ll find something even better in the process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;But my disagreement with this artificial choice goes further.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;m not convinced many people even need to alternate between the two. I think both can be done at the same time. Within the last 5-10 years technologies and mindsets have advanced to a point that allows long-term travel and doing meaningful work to not only NOT be mutually exclusive. In many instances they are complimentary.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I was first working on my solar startup, SolarList, I was living in New York, learning to code and building the product as I learned. I was burning a ton of cash so I shed the overhead of  living in an expensive city. One of the biggest mistakes I made in the startup was moving back and taking on all those costs before SolarList was able to pay salaries. But the geo-arbitrage of living in low cost locations while working through difficult coding problems was the only reason I was able to build and launch my own solar product. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is a &lt;a href=&quot;https://levels.io/bootstrapping-startup-thailand/&quot;&gt;great post here&lt;/a&gt; on all the benefits of building a startup in Thailand. The line items of benefits match point for point with the stuff I&amp;#39;ve been preaching ad nauseum to my friends for years. Read it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maybe you&amp;#39;re not &amp;quot;building a startup.&amp;quot; The concept generalizes further. Most people have a big project they would love to do or at least try: learn to code, write a novel, learn to paint, build their own boat, kickstart a documentary. These things take a lot of time. You can either squeeze in to your busy schedule or find a way to carve out a big block of time to focus on it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My high school girlfriend&amp;#39;s Dad built an airplane in his garage. A freaking airplane! It took him ten years working nights and weekends. I&amp;#39;m not like that. I need to throw myself headlong into a craft to learn it. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I would never be able to consistently carve out a small portion of my schedule and I think a lot of people can&amp;#39;t. Moving to somewhere with a much lower cost of living can give you the flexibility to do that project. When you carve out a sufficiently long enough chunk of time you can play between actively traveling, seeing several cities and moving around a lot, with plunking down in a spot and getting to work every day. Then when you need to recharge, you&amp;#39;re already at your vacation spot. No need to hop on a plane to get that tropical beach time in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;This is a work in progress&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Researching and thinking about this post I thought it would be really crushing to rattle off a list of people who have made long-term travel a part of their lives AND built a meaningful career. But, I honestly couldn&amp;#39;t come up with a great list. Part of that is that I really think the toolkit has only been fully developed. Tools for web collaboration, VOIP, screencasting, collaborative writing, payment processing are all just now getting developed enough to be a truly reliable foundation for remote work. Large parts of the world have only in the last few years laid the infrastructure for fast ubiquitous wifi. So hopefully I&amp;#39;m at the tip of the spear.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But lots of questions remain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I promise more updates as they come in… &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you liked this post, you can &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/intent/tweet?url=http://www.tylertringas.com/meaningful-work-digital-nomads&amp;text=Meaningful Work For Digital Nomads&amp;via=tylertringas&quot;    target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;  share it with your followers&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/tylertringas&quot;&gt;  follow me on Twitter&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 

</feed>
